<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-06T07:45:50+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Stanchion</title><subtitle>Bitching and moaning about the beautiful game</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How do you solve a problem like Mourinho?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/man-united/2018/10/03/how-do-you-solve-a-problem-like-mourinho.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How do you solve a problem like Mourinho?" /><published>2018-10-03T08:00:36+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-03T08:00:36+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/man-united/2018/10/03/how-do-you-solve-a-problem-like-mourinho</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/man-united/2018/10/03/how-do-you-solve-a-problem-like-mourinho.html">&lt;p&gt;Normally I’m the sort of fan who values results over performance. No matter how you get those results, that is what’s most important and a good performance comes secondary as an added bonus. I’ve never understood when fans call into radio phone-ins or bitch and moan on social media about boring football, especially when their team’s doing relatively well because being entertained comes after the whole point of playing the game in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aim of football is to win. At any cost. No matter how you do it, winning is the most important thing. But when you’re &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; winning, and the football is as drab and dreary as United’s has been recently, I can start to see where those fans are coming from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat there watching the Valencia game last night bored out of my skull because we never looked like we were going to get out of first gear. Every player’s performance was at least 20 to 30% off where it should be, the build up was sploddy and lethargic, no one’s making the runs, no one’s linking play and there’s so little movement among the front three or four players it’s unbelievable. Everyone is just static, waiting for someone else to do something and we look a boring side with no ideas and no confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I start to ask, why is that? Why are we so bereft of ideas? It looks to me like we have too many players that don’t fit into the same system, who could be good in the correct systems individually, but when playing together in this team it doesn’t seem to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;left-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/lukaku-valencia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lukaku attempts a stepover vs Valencia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good example of that would be Lukaku. The guy is your archetypal big number 9; he cannot play football with his feet, he’s terrible at dribbling, he has no ability to beat a man, but he’s fast and he’s powerful and his main asset is his strength in the air. When you knowingly buy a player like that you can’t then try to play nice futbol into his feet and use him as a link forward. The way we need to play to get the best out of him is to play with two wingers who’ll get the ball out of their feet and whip balls into the box for him. Even more so when you have Fellaini in the team, as that seems to be something Mourinho is persisting with at the moment. Sadly he’s become one of his most trusted and most used players which is just ridiculous for a club like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More often than not we have wingers playing as full-backs. Valencia and Young are not full-backs but they been converted into that because Mourinho and managers before him don’t trust any of the full-backs that we do have at the club. Valencia is even club captain. This can only be because he’s been at the club the longest amount of time, and we all know Pogba isn’t going to be captain anymore. The lack of real leaders at the club is another worrying factor. If you look back 10 years we had van der Sar, Neville, Ferdinand, Vidic, Evra, Giggs, Rooney. All players who were willing to take responsibility and lead both on and off the pitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other main reason I think we’re playing badly is because the defence is just so shaky and unreliable. None of our centre-backs would get into any other top 4 or 5 side, and because they’re so bad and susceptible to mistakes it makes the rest of the team play with a fear and with the shackles on because they feel like they need to give some sort of protection to the defence. That therefore limits how much we can do going forward, if everyone is starting from such a such a deep position we can’t really play through the thirds cos we’re all in our own third at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, Smalling and Jones have been at the club for 7 or 8 years now, but even the centre-backs Mourinho has brought in himself he doesn’t seem to trust. Lindelof looks so far out of his depth it’s not true and Bailly’s so prone to a mistake. So more often than not he ends up deferring back to Smalling who - as has been widely advertised - can’t play out from the back so there’s no point in just trying to play that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not even sure what kind of football we are trying to play. That’s part of the problem. In days gone by you always knew what you were going to get with United. We were always going to try and score more goals than you. Sometimes we’d let in 2 or 3 but there would always be that sense when you’re watching the game that a goal is coming. Even if you were 2-0 down with 10 minutes to go, you’d still be watching with anticipation that something can and most likely will happen, and more often than not I did. Last night I could see from 10 minutes in that we weren’t going to produce anything and that’s such a mindset change from the Fergie days. It’s really difficult to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past two years I’ve backed Mourinho because although the football has never been good, he has improved our fortunes. We’ve climbed the league from where we were when he took over. We look harder to beat. We even won a couple of trophies, but we seem to be slipping into the Mourinho third year nightmare that he seems to get at every Club. There only looks like one conclusion and I feel like it’s going to happen fairly soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I go through the squad and I can’t think of more than a couple of players that would get into great United sides of the past. The goalkeeper is a definite and he walks into any club team in the world. I really like rashford, he’s young, got a lot of potential, he’s got no fear, he tries to make things happen. The same can be said of Lingard who’s always energetic, always trying to win the ball back high up, trying to make things happen. But I’m not sure who else I’m actually really bothered about in this squad right now. It’s a weird thing to think that only really three of the players I would keep if I could build a new squad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a strange thing to say when the squad contains players like Paul Pogba, Nemanja Matic, Anthony Martial and Alexis Sanchez. I was really excited when we signed Sanchez last year but there hasn’t been one game so far when he’s looked like the guy who used to play for Arsenal. The guy who used to boss games, run games, create goals, score goals, win games all on his own. He looks so far from that player it’s unbelievable and even last night when he got substituted there were cheers from the crowd, which tells you the whole story.  70-odd minutes on the clock, his number comes up and he’s trudging slowly off. Get off the pitch! Let us make the change so we can try and win this match!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sanchez is a strange one because I’m not sure if the player is in a terrible run a form or if the system just doesn’t allow him to do what he wants to do. At Arsenal I think he pretty much had free reign to go and do whatever he wanted, but Mourinho wants him to be much more rigidly stuck to a position and to do defensive duties, which he can’t do as was shown last night. When he was on the right hand side in the first half Valencia got in down that side left time after time and if they had anything about them in the final third we could have been out of the game by half-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not working at the moment and the biggest depiction of all the problems at the club is this ongoing feud between Pogba and Mourinho. They want to keep getting one over on each other, doing silly little gestures to the camera, making snide little remarks in interviews, do stupid things on social media to get one over on the other. This is one of your most influential players in the squad and your manager; they should be the strongest unit in the club, the two of these guys should be always on the same page, always pushing in the same direction, wanting to do the same the best thing for the good of the club. But it looks like all they want to do is drive a wedge between themselves at every opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;right-image&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pogba-valencia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pogba vs Valencia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So something’s going to give eventually. Either Pogba is going to leave or the manager will leave, and considering how much we paid for the player and the potential he has shown in certain games - more often than not for France than for Man United - it would cost the club so much more to lose the player then it would to lose the manager. If you lose the player you’re probably also going to lose the trust and commitment from a lot of other players in the squad because they will stick together. Especially when you got such a tight-knit group of mates like Rashford, Lingard, Pogba and Lukaku. These guys all get on well and you can be sure that they would take each other’s side over the manager, if not publicly then definitely behind closed doors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the manager joined us I was quite pleased because of his proven track record of success and he was the biggest name available to us at the time. He had always coveted the United job too. Up until this summer I thought it was going in the right direction. As I mentioned earlier we weren’t playing the greatest football in the world but we were moving up the league. Ok we were a long way away from city in terms of points, but we were comfortably second. Now though, he seems to be acting like a child at every opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mourinho always digs out the players in the press and then when he’s questioned by journalists about bad performances or bad results he turns things back onto his own track record and what he’s won in the past. Just the other day he was quick to remind the players that nobody’s bigger than the club and said as much in the programme notes for the Valencia game, but in actual fact all he seems to want to do is remind everyone what he’s done in the past and that the most important thing in all of this is Jose Mourinho’s reputation. He’s not bigger than the club. The club will go on without him and hopefully that’s what happens soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So unfortunately I’ve come round to the fact that it might be time for Jose to go. We need a manager who is going to come in and attack teams, bring some flair back, let the shackles off, let the players go and express themselves without the fear of repercussions or a public battering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is meant to be Manchester United. Right now it doesn’t feel like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo: Sky Sports&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Normally I’m the sort of fan who values results over performance. No matter how you get those results, that is what’s most important and a good performance comes secondary as an added bonus. I’ve never understood when fans call into radio phone-ins or bitch and moan on social media about boring football, especially when their team’s doing relatively well because being entertained comes after the whole point of playing the game in the first place.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Switching allegiances</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/england/2017/11/13/switching-allegiances.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Switching allegiances" /><published>2017-11-13T10:00:36+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-13T10:00:36+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/england/2017/11/13/switching-allegiances</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/england/2017/11/13/switching-allegiances.html">&lt;p&gt;I don’t understand how it is that footballers can play an international friendly for one country, but would still be eligible to play for another in competitive matches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I don’t like that fact that players can qualify for multiple countries in the first place. You’re from where you’re from. The way we define that nowadays is much more flexible than it used to be, with multicultural and multi-national families meaning that a player can be born in one country, brought up in another country, have parents and grandparents of separate origins and as a result be eligible for 6 or more national football teams. I find that idea ludicrous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even more ludicrous is how someone can have such little affection for a country that they are willing to play for any nation that they may have a tenuous link to, just so they have the opportunity to play international football. The whole thing is a joke. You just have to look at the Welsh team to see that the majority of them were not born in Wales, have never lived in Wales, and only go to Wales to play international football.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can &lt;em&gt;just about&lt;/em&gt; abide that. Although I do have to admit it feels really insincere, especially when you see videos of the Welsh team celebrating like mad when they watched England getting knocked out of Euro 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I can’t abide is the nation-jumping mentality. Actually, even the fact that it is possible to do that is really irritating to me. Once you have decided who you want to represent you shouldn’t be allowed to change your mind. I think players should be made to make that decision as soon as they sign their first professional contracts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until a player has made a competitive appearance for a country, they are still eligible to play for any other country that they are eligible to play for - if that makes sense. That means they can play international friendlies, and play competitive games all the way up through the age group teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they do switch allegiances I think it shows how much certain players are in it for themselves these days, and they feel like their own personal success is more important than that of the team or the nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look for example at the recent U17 world cup winners. I couldn’t be more excited and optimistic about the future of the England team, and I’m not saying any of them will jump ship to play for another country, but take the photo above as an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every single one of them has turned their shirt around to tell the world what their name is, when they should be proudly showing off the lions on their chest. They won the tournament for England, not themselves. I get that they are starting out and might be looking to get themselves some exposure in order to get a move, but surely they realise scouts will watch their performances back and not just sign young players based on them being in a photo of a trophy presentation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really disappointing and takes a little of the shine off of the trophy they worked so hard and played so brilliantly to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows whether these kids will go on to play for the senior team, or even if they will represent England at all. But the fact that they can win a trophy wearing England’s colours, but still be eligible to play in the senior World Cup for other nations leaves a really unpleasant taste in the mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo: Evening Standard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I don’t understand how it is that footballers can play an international friendly for one country, but would still be eligible to play for another in competitive matches.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unrealistic expectations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/england/2017/10/08/unrealistic-expectations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unrealistic expectations" /><published>2017-10-08T11:00:36+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-08T11:00:36+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/england/2017/10/08/unrealistic-expectations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/england/2017/10/08/unrealistic-expectations.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let’s get this straight right from the off: England are an average international team, and as soon as the public gets that into their collective head we can start to actually enjoy watching them again.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think one of the main reasons that we feel so let down with every abject performance, every scraped result against lowly opposition, every early competition exit, is that we have an elevated opinion of how good we really are as a footballing nation, and where we sit in the real world elite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unremarkable-history&quot;&gt;Unremarkable history&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long and short of it is that we aren’t in the world elite, and we haven’t been for probably 10 years now, since Beckham, Gerrard, Cole and “The Golden Generation” made it to a couple of quarter-finals. To be fair, in several tournaments we weren’t a million miles away. Two quarter-final penalty shoot-out defeats to Portugal in the noughties, another quarter-final loss to eventual world champions Brazil in 2002, and another loss on penalties to Italy in 2012. However in the here and now my personal opinion is that a quarter-final - and certainly a semi-final - would be an overachievement for the current crop of players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;England have no divine right to a place at football’s top table. I feel like there are lots of England fans who think that we should breeze past teams like Iceland and Costa Rica, purely because we have a decent-ish history. Yes we won the World Cup, but success 50+ years ago does not guarantee future generations will be at the same standard. Likewise in the nineties we enjoyed a couple of semi-finals, but if you look back at our performance in major tournaments since ’66, it has been the absolute definition of hit and miss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several times we have had to watch the summer showcases from afar. Indeed, in the 70’s we didn’t go to a single tournament, failing to qualify for Euro ’72, World Cup ’74, Euro ’76 and World Cup ’78. There have been another three qualification failures since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we do get to a tournament the outcome is a real mixed bag. Plenty of group stage exits, plenty of quarter-finals and three semi-finals, but not a single final since ’66.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-importance&quot;&gt;Self importance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a great big national stadium, one of the best domestic league competitions in the world and excellent club sides, and all of this conspires to fool us into thinking our national side should perform with the same excellence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But (the vast majority of) England players are average at best. This has been the case for a while; we’ve only ever had a smattering of real top, top talent. Look at the current squad and ask yourself how many of them would get into any major national side. Harry Kane would walk into most, but apart from him I can only really think of Kyle Walker that might have a shout. We as a viewing public are tricked into thinking that our players are better than they are because of the way they play with their club sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many of Harry Kane’s goals are set up by Christian Eriksen? David Luiz and Cesar Azpilicueta make Gary Cahill look a much better defender than he really is. I don’t think Jordan Henderson actually looks that good in his club side to be honest so that’s him dealt with, and even Adam Lallana - one of our best players at the moment - is servicing a foreign front line at Liverpool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the squad gets together they have to try and knit together all their different styles of play at their clubs and work within the FA’s possession-based “philosophy” that they want filtered through all age groups. And that was only introduced as a decade-late reaction to the fact that Spain won two international trophies in that way, forgetting that Spain were able to field unbelievably gifted, once-in-a-generation footballers who had been schooled in that footballing approach since they were boys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we are genuinely going to implement a top-to-bottom philosophy, we’ll have to wait 10 years or so before we see any fruits from it. The kids who are getting taught that way of playing now at the age or 7 or 8 are the first group who will be able to try and imprint it on the senior squad when they get there. But as we all know we’re impatient for success now, and the same old questions will be asked each and every time we squeak past Lithuania or go out on penalties to Portugal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;England fans have even booed performances and specific players in the past. What the hell is that about?! How do you expect players to perform at their level when they’re being treated like that by &lt;em&gt;their own&lt;/em&gt; fans? It’s disgraceful. As I mentioned before we have no divine right to be smashing teams 4 or 5 nil, or even to play entertaining football.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which leads me onto to the recent qualifying campaign, and why I don’t understand the negativity surrounding the end of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;glass-half-empty&quot;&gt;Glass half empty&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels like we can never have enough to moan about in this country. I’m fed up of people complaining that they want to see more attacking football, or being disgruntled when a defensive minded team is successful. There are so many ways to win football matches, but ultimately that &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the end goal: to win. How you do it is irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entertaining football, beautiful goals and exciting matches is 100% secondary to this. I often hear fans say that they would happily lose every now and then as long as they were being entertained. What total nonsense!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a lot of discontent at the manner of England’s victory versus Slovenia the other night. Let’s look at a couple of reasons why it wasn’t as much of a let-down as some would have you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;England did actually win the game, unless I’m mistaken. Winning that game meant that we qualified for the World Cup. That game was all about getting the job done, and it’s understandable that there was probably a bit of tension in the players, not helped by a negative atmosphere in the stadium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fans were throwing paper planes round the stadium because they were so bored with the match. How about getting behind your team like proper fans do? How about creating an atmosphere that opposition teams don’t want to come and play in? Wembley is so often labelled (by English people I might add) as the home of football. This is probably because we make every other country feel so at home playing there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But back to our qualification performance, how many countries qualified unbeaten, with a game to spare? How many countries qualified conceding just 3 goals in 10 games? How many traditionally big footballing nations haven’t qualified, scraped through or are having to go through playoffs? Holland, Portugal, Italy, Argentina, Chile, Sweden, France. All either just made it, or didn’t make it at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were without several key players for the last two games who would either have started or at least added some competition for places. The likes of Adam Lallana, Danny Rose, Jamie Vardy, Phil Jones and Nathaniel Clyne were all missing. That’s not to mention players currently out of form who - if firing - would add much needed creativity and depth to the squad: Jack Wilshere, Ross Barkley, Danny Welbeck, Andy Carroll… even dare I say, Wayne Rooney?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It blows my mind that the only orthodox centre-midfielders we have had in recent squads have been Henderson, Livermore and Winks. A far cry from the World Cup squad of 2006 where we were able to call on Gerrard, Lampard, Hargreaves, and Carrick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-do-we-do&quot;&gt;So what do we do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like for the majority of games, one holding midfielder is enough. Sometimes even that is too much when you are playing against dentists and butchers in Lithuania. We need to show as little respect to the opposition as possible, and concentrate on what &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; are going to do to beat them. Let them worry about our attacking threats, of which we have many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would play two strikers. Right now that means both Harry Kane and Marcus Rashford are guaranteed starters. They are both having strong seasons for their clubs and I feel they would compliment each other nicely with their differing styles of play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need more players who are willing to take risks and manipulate the ball in the final third. Players who play on the half-turn like Lallana and Wilshere, who can receive the ball and be moving forward instantly. We pay too much attention to ball retention and possession without actually taking any risks and trying anything. I understand that the opposition can’t score when we have the ball, but neither can we if all we do is pass sideways between the centre-backs and centre-midfielders. Moving the ball through the thirds is fine as long as we are doing it quickly and moving the opposition around to create space. Laborious, mundane sideways passing will not win us anything. We are not Spain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it might help if some of our top players actually went and played abroad. Who was the last high profile English player to go and play for anyone in Spain, Italy or even France? David Beckham did it - not through choice - for Real Madrid and became our talisman and a world icon. If more of our players were exposed to other ways of playing we would be a more footballingly intelligent team and be more aware of the kinds of tactics and tricks used by other nations. Just look at how much it has benefitted Gareth Bale and Wales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-starting-11-for-the-world-cup-in-russia&quot;&gt;My starting 11 for the World Cup in Russia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.contentful.com/cqlwgll2y3f0/5Q0adNfLkQOaE6maEWUw4y/dff4cf717916d64c5aa27a6cc2b00800/A81DF633-A2C5-4FD8-AA38-C68FDDBCBA3B.png&quot; alt=&quot;England World Cup 2018&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main image: Evening Standard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Let’s get this straight right from the off: England are an average international team, and as soon as the public gets that into their collective head we can start to actually enjoy watching them again.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You’re ‘ard mate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/discipline/2017/03/07/youre-ard-mate.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You're 'ard mate" /><published>2017-03-07T10:00:36+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-07T10:00:36+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/discipline/2017/03/07/youre-ard-mate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/discipline/2017/03/07/youre-ard-mate.html">&lt;p&gt;What a difference a week makes eh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time last week, Zlatan Ibrahimovic was the toast of the town, the serial winner who almost single-handedly turned a bang average United performance into a cup-winning one. Fast forward 7 days and he’s looking at a ban of at least 3 games for chucking an elbow into Tyrone Mings’ temple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The incident shouldn’t come as a surprise of course. Zlatan has had &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teamtalk.com/news/watch-punching-fighting-slapping-zlatans-unsavoury-past&quot;&gt;many previous instances of being a hard nut&lt;/a&gt;. And it also shouldn’t be a surprise given that barely a minute earlier he had had his head trodden on by Tyrone Mings. However it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; symptomatic of footballers in general to try and prove they’re a hard man, and you see it at every level of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even at the amateur level I play at on a Saturday the nicest bloke in the world can turn into a right knobhead as soon as the first whistle is blown. It’s as if we feel like if we can prove we’re the toughest guy out there we have a better chance of winning, and in many cases that’s probably true. If you think about intimidating your opponent, impressing your authority on a game, and creating a bit of an aura about yourself, you can definitely make yourself harder to beat and get in the other team’s head. But there are ways to go about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every week you’ll hear teams before a match say &lt;em&gt;“let’s not get on the ref’s back early doors, keep him on our side”&lt;/em&gt;, but as soon as the first challenge goes in, or the first dodgy call goes against you that’s it. The world is against us, we’re fired up, and someone’s about to find out about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zlatan’s situation against Bournemouth is a slightly different issue in that during the first 30-odd minutes, he and Mings had been having a bit of a running battle. Then in the aftermath of a Mings tackle on Rooney, he (probably deliberately) stood on Zlatan’s head as he was jumping over him. I’m not here to debate whether Mings meant it or not (he did), as that’s a topic for another day, but Zlatan clocked who had wronged him, and was not going to have to wait long to exact revenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact it was at the very next phase of play. I’m not even sure if the two had been marking each other until that point, but of course they found themselves challenging for the same ball at a corner. Zlatan sees Mings coming and throws a big unnatural elbow into his head as he challenges for the ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both players will receive lengthy bans and rightly so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My issue as a United fan is that in his efforts to get his own back on Mings and prove how hard he is, Zlatan has now seriously jeopardised our chances in two competitions. If - as looks likely - he receives a three game ban, he will miss two Premier League games at a crucial stage of the season when we’re chasing 4th place, and the FA Cup quarter final against the best team in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As probably the most experienced and senior player in the squad, he should be only too aware of how important he’s been to the team this season. He’s won us games we haven’t deserved to win and had it not been for his goals we’d probably be in mid table mediocrity. So to go and get himself banned is irresponsible in the extreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only positive that will come out of Zlatan’s inevitable suspension is that Marcus Rashford is likely to get some game time through the middle, where he was so very effective when he broke into the team last season. I  hope for the sake of our season that Rashford can do the business, and that Zlatan’s absence doesn’t simply make the heart grow fonder for his return.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What a difference a week makes eh?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Free Agents FC</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/transfers/2017/02/02/free-agents-fc.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Free Agents FC" /><published>2017-02-02T10:00:36+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-02T10:00:36+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/transfers/2017/02/02/free-agents-fc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/transfers/2017/02/02/free-agents-fc.html">&lt;p&gt;The transfer window has been shut for a week now, but clubs can still sign players who don’t currently have a club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I thought it’d be interesting to see what sort of a side I could put together made up of current free agents (that I have heard of) and see if they’d actually be any good. These players were available as of 07/02/2017 according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.transfermarkt.co.uk/spieler/vertragslosespieler/statistik/1/plus//galerie/0?ausrichtung=alle&amp;amp;spielerposition_id=alle&amp;amp;land_id=alle&amp;amp;wettbewerb_id=alle&amp;amp;seit=alle&amp;amp;yt0=Show&quot;&gt;Transfermarkt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve gone for a trendy 4-2-3-1 formation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keeper---chris-kirkland-35&quot;&gt;Keeper - Chris Kirkland (35)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There aren’t many well known keepers in the list, but I’ve gone with Chris Kirkland. He’s hugely experienced and in a 16 year career to date has played for Coventry, Wigan, in the Champions League for Liverpool, and made one appearance for England. He was actually Liverpool’s first choice keeper for the 2004-05 season before a back injury forced him to miss out on the club’s historic Champions League comeback in Istanbul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;right-back---maicon-35&quot;&gt;Right back - Maicon (35)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maicon should be pretty well known to fans of European football. He was best known for playing at Inter Milan where he was a marauding right back for 6 years. During that time he was consistently Brazil’s first choice, winning the Copa America twice and the Confederations cup twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man City fans probably remember him for a fairly dismal stint at the Etihad when he was heading towards the twilight of his career. In fact they’d probably rather forget him. But in his day he was very decent, and was the proper modern day full back - basically playing as a winger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;centre-back---martin-cacéres-29&quot;&gt;Centre back - Martin Cacéres (29)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s always a surprise to find a player out of contract when they’ve played at the top level and are still only 29 years old, but that’s the case with Martin Cacéres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cacéres actually spent a short stint at Barcelona in the late noughties, but only appeared 13 times for the club in between loan spells at Juventus and Sevilla. He’s since had permanent contracts at both of those clubs too and has spent the last 4 seasons at Juve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing Southampton are showing some reported interest in a short term deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;centre-back---christopher-samba-32&quot;&gt;Centre back - Christopher Samba (32)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Samba had about one season when he was at Blackburn when he was an absolute monster of a defender. After that he spent time at Anzhi in Russia as well as QPR, and wasn’t able to recapture the form he showed during that short spell in Lancashire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, he’s only 32 which is the peak of a defender’s career, so you’d be surprised if someone doesn’t snap hin up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;left-back---kieran-richardson-32&quot;&gt;Left back - Kieran Richardson (32)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kieran Richardson has 8 England caps. That’s mental.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 5 or 6 years at Manchester United he came through the youth ranks and was regularly used as a backup left back and occasional backup left winger but he was never going to be good enough to be a regular starter. He picked up a Premier League winner’s medal in 2007 and was then sold the season before United won the Champions League.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s since spent time at Sunderland, Fulham, Villa and Cardiff, and could probably do a good job for someone at Championship level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;centre-midfield---kim-kallstrom-34&quot;&gt;Centre midfield - Kim Kallstrom (34)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a time when Kim Kallstrom was the first purchase for anyone starting a new career on Football Manager. In the mid noughties he was a solid but probably undervalued centre midfielder who could be snapped up for a bargain by savvy virtual Alex Fergusons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s best known for his spell at Lyon where he played in a successful team with the likes of Juninho Pernambucano (the one who was ace at free kicks), Eric Abidal, Florent Malouda, Karim Benzema and his midfield partner in this team…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;centre-midfield---michael-essien-34&quot;&gt;Centre midfield - Michael Essien (34)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essien was a cornerstone of Jose Mourinho’s first Chelsea team, and won the Premier League twice, FA Cup four times, and Champions League while was at Stamford Bridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then went on to play for Real Madrid, Milan and Panathinaikos. For a while Essien was almost the complete midfielder - tough in the tackle, an eye for a pass and always popped up with his fair share of goals. Definitely one that got away from United’s point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;right-wing---charles-nzogbia-30&quot;&gt;Right wing - Charles N’Zogbia (30)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N’Zogbia could have been knocking on the door of world class if he ever achieved anything like his true potential. When he burst onto the scene with Newcastle it looked like he was destined for the top but well publicised issues with his attitude and lack of real application held him back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spells with Newcastle, Wigan and Villa show that he never really made it to the top. Bit of a weird inclusion in this team but I was struggling to find a right winger that I had heard of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attacking-midfield---julio-baptista-35&quot;&gt;Attacking midfield - Julio Baptista (35)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another player that you could argue never truly reached the levels it looked like he was capable of. “The Beast” surprisingly started out in Brazil as a defensive midfielder but was converted to an attacker when he joined Sevilla in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then got a big money move to Real Madrid but it never quite worked out for him. He had semi-successful but largely forgettable loan spell at Arsenal - including 4 goals in a League Cup game vs Liverpool - before returning to Madrid and producing lacklustre spells at 4 other clubs. His power and pace should have seen him up there with the best but it never really happened for The Beast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;left-wing---royston-drenthe-29&quot;&gt;Left wing - Royston Drenthe (29)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another relatively young player to be without a club, Drenthe was at one time the hottest property in Europe with all the big boys linked with his signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He signed for Real Madrid - a place it seems a few players with potential go to not live up to their potential - and fell out with Jose Mourinho, and went on loan to Everton where he fell out with David Moyes for repeatedly being late for training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing he’s without a club, but I’ve read that he also fancies himself as a rapper, so we’ll see how that works out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;striker---didier-drogba-38&quot;&gt;Striker - Didier Drogba (38)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a bit spoilt for choice in this position - Robbie Keane and Dimitar Berbatov are both available too - but I think I’ve made the right choice in Didier Drogba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drogba’s probably pushing it a bit now in terms of his age - he’s unlikely to get any offers from top clubs, but in a change from the majority of this team,  at least here is a player who definitely made it to the top of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drogba was probably the most feared striker in the Premier League for a 7 to 8 year period while he was at Chelsea. He won everything there is to win the the club, including slotting home the winning penalty in the shootout to win the 2012 Champions League final. He bagged over 100 Premier League goals and I hated him from the day he signed for Chelsea to the day he left. Purely because he played for them and not us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you reckon? Ten years ago this would have been an immense side I feel could give anyone a game. Most of them are probably over the hill now, but I reckon a few of them still have something to offer the right club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image: http://images.elephantjournal.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The transfer window has been shut for a week now, but clubs can still sign players who don’t currently have a club.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Not as easy as you thought?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/man-city/2017/01/16/not-as-easy-as-you-thought.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Not as easy as you thought?" /><published>2017-01-16T10:00:36+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-16T10:00:36+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/man-city/2017/01/16/not-as-easy-as-you-thought</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/man-city/2017/01/16/not-as-easy-as-you-thought.html">&lt;p&gt;About four years ago I wrote a post questioning Pep Guardiola’s status as one of the world’s best managers. You can read that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thestanchion.co.uk/destination-england&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but in the interests of time a couple of the main points were…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It remains to be seen whether or not he could take a team and make them play in a style that suits the players at his disposal.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Could it just be pure coincidence that as Guardiola took charge, he was able to use midfielders like Xavi, Iniesta, Busquets, Messi; all world class players who have been schooled in that style of play from an early age at the club academy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be a perfect opportunity for me to say I told you so, but I do actually think that the next 4 or 5 months to the end of this season could go a long way to proving just how good of a manager Pep really is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;City made a very good start to life under Guardiola. They won their first 10 games in all competitions, including the first 6 league games to put themselves top of the early season table. Things were looking good. But that run came to an end when they lost 2-0 away at Spurs and since then, results have been very inconsistent and they’ve slipped to 5th in the league at the time of writing. The most recent result - a 4-0 loss away at Everton - must surely act as a massive wake up call to the manager that his team is in need of some improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all honesty, anybody can lose at Everton. This season they’re a very solid proposition and have had several good results against teams towards the top of the league, including a 2-1 comeback win over Arsenal. But it’s the scoreline and the manner of the defeat that was so surprising. Everton were stronger all over the pitch and completely dominated, fully deserving the win and making City look more like a team fighting relegation than one hunting for top honours. There are a few things that are contributing to City’s patchy form and that Pep seems reluctant to change, despite the fact that they seem obvious to the casual observer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brav-oh-no&quot;&gt;Brav-oh no&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claudio Bravo was one of the first names through the door at the Etihad once Guardiola took the reigns, and Joe Hart was quickly ushered through that same door in the opposite direction. This is looking more and more like an almighty clanger and conveniently, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/38684434&quot;&gt;stats published by the BBC today&lt;/a&gt; back up that statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bravo has performed in the bottom five of the 23 Premier League keepers to have faced more than 100 shots this season. In the last 8 games he’s conceded 14 goals, and according to the science bods at Opta, that is 7 more than the number he would be “expected” to save, based on factors such as quality of chance, distance from goal, angle, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody can say with 100% certainty that Joe Hart would have saved any of the additional 7, but it does highlight what I think is a key flaw in Guardiola’s selection of a goalkeeper - namely that keeping goal is a secondary requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Hart, for all his arrogance and dandruff, is a fine goalkeeper. Claudio Bravo, as has become apparent, is not in the same bracket when it comes to shot stopping and decision making. For me when you’re picking a goalkeeper, the primary factor in your thinking should be which one will save the most shots, and therefore give us the best chance of winning a game. Guardiola on the other hand has his clear footballing philosophy first and foremost in his mind which as we know starts with a goalkeeper who is comfortable with the ball at his feet. Bravo fits the bill here, but the Premier League is a very different beast to La Liga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Spain, the energy levels and pressing game are not as intense as they are here. When he was playing for Barcelona, Bravo could get away with an errant touch here and there and more often than not it wouldn’t lead to anything. Now, the merest loose touch can be capitalised on and whilst it won’t necessarily lead to a goal, it can give a lot of belief to opposition players and supporters. The atmosphere of a game can completely change with that sort of thing. Footballing skill in a goalkeeper should be a nice-to-have attribute. Not a pre-requisite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;john-stones-doesnt-look-quite-ready-yet&quot;&gt;John Stones doesn’t look quite ready yet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Stones was another big money signing at the beginning of Pep’s time in Manchester, but again it hasn’t quite worked out for him as well as he probably hoped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stones is a good player, no doubt (although he isn’t worth anywhere near £50 million). But last season with Everton and this season so far have shown that he isn’t quite ready to be considered in the top bracket of centre backs, even those available to England.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to Bravo, Stones’ first instinct is to try and play football, passing or dribbling out from the back. He is competent at doing this but there are too many times when he shows immaturity in picking when to play, and when to just get rid. Again, he is a defender so defending should surely be his top priority. It’s admirable that he wants to try to keep the ball and start attacks for his team, but he needs coaching as to when it is correct to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stones has been a fairly constant selection for City this season. I expect if Vincent Kompany had been fit for longer that this may not have been the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;barca-style-of-play&quot;&gt;Barca style of play&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guardiola’s philosophy of tiki-taka football, which worked so well in Barcelona and Munich, is struggling to be adopted by his new side, but he perseveres with it despite this. It’s easy with several world class players, playing in one or two team leagues to achieve success playing like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that style isn’t suited to his current squad, and arguably isn’t suited to the Premier League, so it will be interesting to see if he changes tack to try and get the best out of the players he does have, or continues doing what he’s doing. I get the feeling that he’s very steadfast in his footballing beliefs, or to put it another way, stubborn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really hope we see him try to fix his problems by actually managing the players he has, rather than going into the market to buy ready made solutions from elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">About four years ago I wrote a post questioning Pep Guardiola’s status as one of the world’s best managers. You can read that here, but in the interests of time a couple of the main points were…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kane in the neck</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tottenham/2015/05/31/kane-in-the-neck.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kane in the neck" /><published>2015-05-31T11:00:36+01:00</published><updated>2015-05-31T11:00:36+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tottenham/2015/05/31/kane-in-the-neck</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tottenham/2015/05/31/kane-in-the-neck.html">&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things wrong with the English sporting media, but one thing in particular has wound me up this week and its something that happens every time there’s a young English player in a rich vein of form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current hot topic is of course Harry Kane. He’s having a stellar season so far – 29 goals in all competitions for Spurs, and a goal within 80 seconds of his England debut – and this is in no way aimed at him. My issue is that because he’s having a brilliant season, if you listen to the media you’d think he’s Spurs and England’s only player. It’s a culture and way of thinking in England that I believe holds us back and blinds us as to what our true level is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the build up to Tottenham’s recent game against Man United all the talk referring to Spurs was about whether Kane could get his first goal versus United. Not about Spurs recent run of good form, how they might approach the game, or any other key battles between players across the pitch. Similarly last week the only talk was about why Kane should start, why he shouldn’t start, whether he’s ready, whether he’s not. It was as if, before he’s even had as much as one international minute, all England needed to do was put Kane in the team and the result would take care of itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only 9 months ago we were in Brazil with a squad containing the new generation of English players.  But as soon as there’s a new addition to that group of youngsters, all the others are seemingly forgotten. Kane should be spoken about as part of our future, alongside players like Sterling, Barkely, Clyne and Stones. He’s not our only player, we need to support the whole team and not just focus on the flavour of the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Kane had been included in the squad, pundits were debating whether he should be in the starting 11. The argument focussed on the fact that he’s the most in form English striker, with more Premier League goals than Rooney, Sturridge and Welbeck combined. I agree that on form he should be in the team, but up until now England have won every game since the World Cup, and Roy has a trusted team with a working system. Why change it if it’s been working well up to now? I can see both sides of this argument but when the form of the team has been good, I can’t understand the amount of people wanting to change it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And once the team has been picked and the game is under way, we don’t have to hear his name every 30 seconds! They had cameras on him during the anthems, they cut straight to Kane clapping when Rooney scored, showed him warming up and stretching. I understand the clamour for him – or any young Engish talent – to be a superstar, but let’s give the kid a chance. Let’s give him some time to fully establish himself as a first team club player before we decide he’s the answer to our prayers. A lot of people would do well to remember that this is still his first proper season as a Premier League regular. I’m not saying the same thing will happen but there are a lot of players, Kevin Phillips for example, who were prolific at club level but couldn’t quite cut it at international level. Like everyone else, I hope Kane becomes a star for England, I just think we need to be a bit more level headed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we need to stop pinning our hopes on individual players every time a new one comes along. Too often we rely on a Rooney or a Beckham to drag us through tournaments, when we should really be considering how good we are as a team and basing our expectations on that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">There are a lot of things wrong with the English sporting media, but one thing in particular has wound me up this week and its something that happens every time there’s a young English player in a rich vein of form.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Home and Away</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/premier-league/2014/10/14/home-and-away.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Home and Away" /><published>2014-10-14T11:00:36+01:00</published><updated>2014-10-14T11:00:36+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/premier-league/2014/10/14/home-and-away</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/premier-league/2014/10/14/home-and-away.html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s get this straight right from the start: The idea of playing a Premier League game in a foreign country is stupid, unrealistic, probably unfair and just unnecessary. It’s just the latest idea that the money hungry suits who run the league have cooked up in order to further line their already bulging pockets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the risk of sounding like a little Englander, this is our league. It is the English Premier League. It should remain in England. If this is allowed to happen, how long will it be before we have 2, 3 or 4 games per season played abroad?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The arguments in favour seem to point to the success the NFL have had for a few years now, taking one game to Wembley every season. The stadium sells out and the game gets a huge amount of t.v. coverage. However you never hear about what the American fans think about it over here. The NFL season is much shorter than our football season – around 16 games – so you’d have to imagine that they are pretty pissed. To only have 8 games at home per season in the first place, and then to have one of those games taken away from you for the sake of some billionaire owners’ bank account? If I was a season ticket holder I’d go mad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t get the chance to go to Old Trafford very often at all, but I still hate the idea of a home game being taken away. Part of the magic of going to watch your team is the trip to the stadium. Actually going to your team’s home ground. When I get the rare opportunity to go I’m just as excited about that moment when you walk up the steps into the stand, as I am about seeing the players, anticipating a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the subject of fairness, it isn’t just the fans that would lose out. Who decides which games are played overseas for example? There’s no way that a fixture abroad can be arranged so that it would be fair to every club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a team only needed 1 point to avoid relegation, who decides whether their game abroad is against Chelsea or Burnley, potentially the difference between survival and the trap-door to the Championship? You can bet that derby games would definitely not be moved, but why are these games any more important in the scheme of things? They are all worth three points to the winners, so they should all have equal importance. None should be turned into a glorified friendly in some far flung corner of the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple beauty of the league structure is the way that everybody plays each other twice, once at our place and once at yours. Whilst the overseas game would clearly be played at a neutral ground, the identity of a club’s opponents would definitely be something that managers would contest. They’ll find qualms with whichever team they face, it’s in their nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Playing at home is a huge advantage for some clubs, and often home form is the defining factor in how a club fares over a season. Reducing that advantage even slightly seems unfair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The club should belong to the community. Yes, they all want to gain more fans which in turn produces more revenue, but most teams already go on tours, so there is no real case for expanding global reach. The league is already a worldwide sensation, you only have to watch comic relief to see the reach of the league’s popularity, when an African kid runs past in an Arsenal shirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ticket prices are already way too high and prohibitive to a lot of families being able to see live football. Taking games abroad only increases the problem. The clubs and the league don’t need the money but this is the only reason I can think of that they have for wanting to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe at most you could play one of the existing glorified friendlies abroad, the community shield would be a perfect example. This has been done with some success in other countries already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But going back to the original point. This is the English Premier League. It has to stay in England.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo: doingthe116.wordpress.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Let’s get this straight right from the start: The idea of playing a Premier League game in a foreign country is stupid, unrealistic, probably unfair and just unnecessary. It’s just the latest idea that the money hungry suits who run the league have cooked up in order to further line their already bulging pockets.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Send for reinforcements</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/man-united/2014/08/28/send-for-reinforcements.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Send for reinforcements" /><published>2014-08-28T11:00:36+01:00</published><updated>2014-08-28T11:00:36+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/man-united/2014/08/28/send-for-reinforcements</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/man-united/2014/08/28/send-for-reinforcements.html">&lt;p&gt;The season is barely a week old and it’s already glaringly obvious that United need to spend money, or face up to another season of mediocrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the second summer running, Ed Woodward flew home early from the pre-season tour to conduct transfer business. Yet all we’ve heard since then is that there have been no official bids for any players. How can that be? If last season wasn’t enough of a wake up call, this summer further reinforces the need for help, especially in defence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Losing Rio, Vida, Pat and Giggsy from the playing squad all in one summer is a phenomenal blow both in terms of quality but also sheer experience. All of these players are European and multiple Premier League champions. You can’t replace that overnight but you can certainly attempt to plug gaps in what is an obviously fragile spine in need of urgent attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday’s game against Swansea served as a big wet slap in the face after the false promise of a very successful pre-season tour where we won every game, including victories against such European giants as Real Madrid, Liverpool and Inter Milan. Yes, it was an impressive showing in the USA, but you have to consider that the majority of these sides were missing big name players due to extended breaks after the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Louis’ favoured 3-5-2 looked to have promise in America but in practice I can’t see it working in the Premier League. Manchester United simply don’t have the players to fit the system, and one of the basic theories of the game is to play to the strengths of the players at your disposal. Nearly every player in that squad will have been brought up, and will have spent most of their career, using formations based on a solid back 4. They all know it, know their roles within it, and know where they should be in all situations. 3-5-2 won’t work with United’s current squad because we only have 3 senior centre-backs, and none of them are currently top class footballers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That point was highlighted on Saturday by Tyler Blackett’s performance. He has got a lot of promise but not on the left side of a back 3. He was caught out of position for Swansea’s first goal, and showed a lack of experience for their second goal by passing the ball back to them after a foul, allowing them to take a quick free kick, which ended up leading to the winning goal for Sigurdsson. A more experienced player would have left the ball where it was, allowing his team mates to get back into position and be better prepared to defend the next attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that being said our starting 11 on paper should still be sweeping Swansea aside without much fuss. It just goes to show that the old addage of the game not being played on paper is very true, especially at Old Trafford these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This team is crying out for help in two main positions as far as I see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need at least one experienced, top-class centre-back to organise that defence and provide some much needed protection for David De Gea. Last season he was voted United’s player of the year, which was well deserved because he was the only player to come out of the season with any credit, making a string of incredible saves. But the sheer fact that a goalkeeper should be considered Manchester United’s player of the year is a very clear reflection on the way the rest of the team played. Terribly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second area is no surprise, defensive midfield. Michael Carrick’s absence is hurting us at the moment, but even he isn’t the kind of player we need. United have lost their fear factor and not since Roy Keane have we had a real hard man in the middle of the park. Someone who scares opposition defences into submission, but also scares his team mates into better performances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcos Rojo is a decent addition but in the wrong position. We just spent £30 million on Luke Shaw, so I don’t see the sense in buying another left sided defender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pull your finger out Ed, while you still have the chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo – mirror.co.uk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The season is barely a week old and it’s already glaringly obvious that United need to spend money, or face up to another season of mediocrity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New year’s reservations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/man-united/2014/01/23/new-years-reservations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New year's reservations" /><published>2014-01-23T10:00:36+00:00</published><updated>2014-01-23T10:00:36+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/man-united/2014/01/23/new-years-reservations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/man-united/2014/01/23/new-years-reservations.html">&lt;p&gt;This post is a bit ranty, so apologies in advance. I’ve had a lot of these thoughts brewing for a while and thought I may as well vent it all in an attempt to come to terms with our current troubling form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-the-defence&quot;&gt;For the defence&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll include David De Gea here as he is technically part of the defence. In short I think he’s ace. The improvement seen in him since he first arrived in 2011 is enormous and he was rightly included in the team of the season for 2012/13. He made a massive clanger against Sunderland which effectively led to us going out of the cup, and it was an unforgivable error for a keeper of his calibre, but you could argue we shouldn’t have been in that position in the first place. De Gea has been one of the only positive and consistent things in the season so far, and I dare say we’d be a few points further off the pace without him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next one is particularly difficult for me to type, but as much as I love him I fear Patrice Evra’s days are numbered. All to often this season he’s caught out of position, not close enough to his man and too lazy tracking back. He’s really effective in attacking positions, as his improved goal return in the last two seasons shows, but I don’t feel as confident in him defensively as I used to. This could be his last season as first choice left-back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rio and, to a lesser extent Vida, both now have their best days long behind them. With Ferdinand the main problem is a sever lack of pace tied to being pretty injury prone. I think that it would be worth having him in the squad because he’s such a character and presence in the dressing room, but he shouldn’t start games any more. Nemanja Vidic is still a very good defender, and should be kept in the squad and probably play a large number of games, but as with Ferdinand he has lost at least a yard of in recent seasons; such a key attribute in the modern game. His experience and ability should be used to help develop the defence for the future, which should be built around Phil Jones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phil Jones has been played predominantly out of position since he arrived at Old Trafford. When you sign a teenager for £16 million, you imagine that he is pretty god for his age in his position. Jones had been starting for Blackburn in the Premier League which shows the quality he had. So it seems weird to me that he’s played a massive percentage of his games for United in midfield. On occasion he can do a good job, when he is given a man to mark and follow for a game, like he did to great effect against Cristiano Ronaldo last season. But he lacks the subtlety and finesse with the ball at his feet to be a midfielder in the long term. If you look at the best ‘destroyer’ type midfielders – Claude Makelele is a prime example – they all have some amount of ability to find a simple pass and retain possession. This is not in Jones’ core set of skills. He is at his best when he’s making last ditch challenges, smothering shots, winning headers and bossing strikers. He is a centre back, who was bought as a centre back, who plays best at centre back, but gets played in midfield. This isn’t all David Moyes fault, the precedent was set by Alex Ferguson, but Moyes can fix it by building his new defence around Jones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;midfield&quot;&gt;Midfield&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our wingers are average at best. Tony Valencia is one of the most indecisive players I’ve seen. He is an absolute monster with pace to burn, but 95% of the time he’ll get to the edge of the box and then take half an hour to decide what to do, before turning and passing to his right back. Plus he’s massively inconsistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ashley young is poor and needs to be sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might be one of only a few people who thinks that Nani is ok when he’s not injured. He’s one of the only players in the squad who can actually square up a man and send him the wrong way, but his end product and goal return is severely lacking. Plus, he’s injured all the time lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do you start with Marouane Fellaini? Our only major signing of the summer, he has looked so out of place in the big games. Against Yaya in the derby he was out muscled, out powered, out-run, outplayed and generally outclassed. Out of his depth. He was a good player at an average club at Everton. He doesn’t improve United’s squad in any way and was a panic buy. The less said about him the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cleverley looked promising in his early United career but has only developed into an OK player at best. His ball retention is generally good but quite often silly mistakes creep into his game. He plays sideways too often and his goal return is also pretty woeful for a player who must have aspirations of being the answer to the CAM problem for the next decade. It’s an obvious thing to say but United need a player who can keep the ball but also play incisive, defence-splitting passes forward. They need a Scholes. Cleverley will never be a Scholes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fletch is ok as an understudy but like Cleverley he only plays sideways and never finds incisive through balls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carrick is only CM worth keeping for a starting place. He has a fantastic range of passing, instigates attacks with forward balls plus he makes a huge amount of interceptions. If only he could shoot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adnan Januzaj is the big positive from this season. He has almost single-handedly kept the season alive, and perhaps to a greater extent kept the fans interested in a season which could soon be all over bar the shouting if results don’t improve. His five year contract is a massive boost and hopefully he goes on to become our next iconic number seven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attack-attack-attack&quot;&gt;Attack, Attack, Attack&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally I think we’re ok up top if everyone is fit. This season does need a certain amount of perspective on account of the fact that van Persie and Rooney have been injured for huge chunks of it. Any team would miss those two and the stats from games where they play together back that up. I think we’d be a good six to eight points better off if they had been available for every game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it has been highlighted in the press but one huge problem is that we don’t have those huge final ten to fifteen minute spells any more when you feel like a goal was just a case of WHEN and not IF. I think that can all be linked to confidence, which I personally believe is caused by the defence being shaky all season. The midfield and attackers (Rooney) aren’t getting forward enough late in games because they’re more worried about conceding. In years gone by we’d have ten players in the opposition half for the final ten minutes of a game we were chasing, it’s not happening at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cheers-fergie&quot;&gt;Cheers Fergie&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that he is a trophy-winning monster, Fergie left us in the shit big time with no attacking midfielder of note and an ageing defence. When he pulled Paul Scholes out of retirement two years ago it should have acted as a massive slap in the face to the fact that we were dying for that kind of player. Instead, Scholes stayed on another season and the problem was forgotten about and left for the next manager to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I think this season isn’t all David Moyes’ fault, and why he fans have stayed behind him so far, but he has a lot of work to do. The signing of Juan Mata is an excellent start and hopefully he can integrate into the team quickly, starting tonight at home to Cardiff.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This post is a bit ranty, so apologies in advance. I’ve had a lot of these thoughts brewing for a while and thought I may as well vent it all in an attempt to come to terms with our current troubling form.</summary></entry></feed>